indiancag.org 2016-05-02

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy 

This privacy policy (“ **Policy** “) discloses the practices and policies adopted by Association of Citizens for Accountable Governance, a company registered under section 25 of the Indian Companies Act (“ **CAG** “) for collecting, storing, retrieving or using Personal Information (as defined in clause 1 of this Policy) and Sensitive Personal Information (as defined in clause 1 of this Policy) it may receive from its Users (as defined in clause 1 of this Policy) for creating a volunteer base of CAG.

 All terms and conditions regarding use of the website http://www.indiancag.org/(“ **Website** “) are incorporated in this Policy by reference. The Policy seeks to comply with the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Data or Information) Rules, 2011 (“ **Rules** “).

**This Policy is applicable to all Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information that is disclosed by Users at the time of registration with CAG as a volunteer,promotion, survey or other site feature through the Website. CAG reserves the right to modify or review the provisions in this Policy without prior notice. Therefore, the Users are requested to periodically visit the Website for updates relating to amendments to this Policy.**

BY USING THE CAG WEBSITE YOU HEREBY ACCEPT THE TERMS OF THIS POLICY AND GRANT CONSENT FOR PROVIDING PERSONAL INFORMATION AND SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION TO CAG IN RELATION TO REGISTRATION WITH CAG AS PROVIDED IN THIS POLICY.

**1\. DEFINITIONS**

“ **Applicable Law** “ means all applicable statutes, acts of Indian legislature, ordinances, rules, bye-laws, regulations, notifications, circulars, guidelines, policies, directions, directives and orders of any government, statutory authority, regulatory authority, tribunal, board or court in India;

“ **General Information** “ will have the same meaning ascribed to it in clause 4.1 of the Policy;

“ **Personal Information** “ means the information disclosed by a User at the time of registration with CAG and includes name, age, photograph, email address, college attended, residential address, telephone number and any other personal details, which are capable of identifying the User;

“ **Sensitive Personal Information** “ will, excluding any information that is freely available or accessible in public domain or is furnished under applicable laws of India, mean the following information, for processing the request of registration with CAG:

**(a) password of the User;**

“ **Terms of Use** “ means the terms and conditions mentioned on the Website;  
“ **User** “ means any person who has registered on the Website with CAG as a volunteer or a Visitor;  
“ **Visitor** “ means any person who visits or uses or accesses or browses the Website in any manner whatsoever; and  
“ **Website(s)** “ will have the same meaning ascribed to it in the preamble to the Policy.

**2\. Collection of Personal Information**

2.1 A User, in order to register with CAG, is required to reveal Personal Information while registering on the Website. CAG will collect Personal Information from a User when he/she fills out a volunteer registration form.

2.2 CAG will ensure that Personal information and the Sensitive Personal Information provided by the User is kept secure and in accordance with the Terms of Use and this Policy.

2.3 The Personal Information will be used by CAG only for communication with the Users, to administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature,maintaining a confidential database of Users and passing on information to the User in relation to the activities of CAG.

2.4 CAG is not responsible for the correctness or completeness of the Personal Information or any consequences arising due to the disclosure of incorrect or incomplete Personal Information. Further, the User will keep CAG or its affiliates, shareholders, their respective officers and employees, and any service providers or contractors indemnified against any losses, actions or consequences arising due to furnishing of such incorrect or incomplete Personal Information made by such User.

2.5 If the User does not wish to provide Personal Information or withdraws the Personal Information provided earlier, the User may not be registered with CAG as a volunteer.

**3\. COLLECTION OF SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

3.1 A User may be required to reveal Sensitive Personal Information while registering/logging in on the Website.

3.2 Sensitive Personal Information will be used by CAG only for the purposes of registration with CAG, maintaining a confidential database of Users and passing on information to the User in relation to the activities of CAG. Sensitive Personal Information will not be used by CAG for any commercial purposes.

3.3 Once Sensitive Personal Information has been provided to CAG, User has the option of amending the Sensitive Personal Information provided earlier.

3.4 If the User does not wish to provide Sensitive Personal Information, the User may not be permitted to register with CAG as a volunteer.

**4\. GENERAL INFORMATION**

4.1 While browsing through the Website, the Website’s server may automatically record some general information about User’s visit, such as the date and time of visiting the Websites, the IP address being used, the type of browser being used etc. (“General Information”). Such General Information collected is not Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information and the Website’s server does not link such General Information with the Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information furnished by the User.

4.2 CAG reserves the right to use General Information collected by it for any purpose whatsoever including statistical analysis, marketing and promotional purposes. Consequently, CAG may share such General Information or any analysis with any person, at its sole discretion.

**5\. COOKIES**

When a User visits the Website, one or more cookies will be sent to the computer or the device being used by the User. The Cookies are used to improve the quality of the Website, including for storing User preferences, improving search results and tracking User trends. The User has the option of disabling cookies via their browser preferences. However, Users are advised and made aware that if they disable cookies on their browser, some parts of Website may not function as effectively.

**6\. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION AND SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

6.1 Only the persons authorized by CAG will have access to Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information disclosed to CAG. The User by registering with CAG, grants consent to CAG for sharing the information with third parties, persons or entities, associated with CAG, provided such persons or entities have undertaken to ensure the same level of data protection as CAG. CAG will share only information that is necessary in relation to activities and initiatives of CAG and administering a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature. The User may withdraw its consent at any time by sending a request in writing to CAG. However, upon withdrawal of such consent, the User may not be permitted to participate in any CAG related activities.

 6.2 Notwithstanding anything contained in this Policy, CAG reserves the right to disclose any Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information that may be required to be disclosed under Applicable Law, without prior notice or consent of the User.

 6.3 CAG cannot guarantee that third parties will keep the Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information confidential and CAG will not be held liable in any manner for any loss of confidentiality attributable to such third parties.

**7\. SECURITY**

7.1 CAG has taken all reasonable measures and precautions to keep the Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information safe and secure and to prevent any unauthorized access to or misuse of the same.

7.2 CAG is not liable to any User for any loss, damage (whether direct, indirect, consequential or incidental) or harm caused to any User due to the unauthorized access or misuse of the Personal Information or Sensitive Personal information by any third party (beyond the control of CAG). CAG has a comprehensive and documented information security program that contains managerial, technical, operational and physical security control measures.

**8\. ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY**

This online Policy applies only to information collected through our Website and not to information collected offline.

**9\. CHANGES TO POLICY**

If any changes to this Policy are made, CAG will post those changes on the Website and update the Policy modification date below.

**10\. LINKING TO OTHER SITES**

CAG will not be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other websites for which links may be provided on the Website. By clicking on a link, logo or other such items, or using certain services available on the other website, the User may no longer be on the Website and in such circumstances privacy policy of such other website will apply.

**11\. CONTACT US**

If there are any questions regarding this Policy a User may contact CAG using the information below.
